Mohammed Shifreen

Full Stack Web Developer

Mobile No: +974 66033406 GitHub: https://github.com/Shifrin

Email: mshifreen@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mshifreen/

Website: http://mshifreen.com StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/1933627/shifrin

Personal Statement

I'm a skilful Full Stack Web Developer with proficient computer literature who currently living in Qatar. I'm having more than 6 years of experience in developing web-based applications & websites based on PHP, MySQL, Yii Framework and WordPress. And also, my experience includes web designing based on HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, jQuery, Twitter Bootstrap & UiKit. And more I do have experience in RTL layouts and Arabic content websites.

I have worked on various projects and gained good experience in developing web-based applications & websites and had a proper understanding of Yii & Yii2 Frameworks and WordPress during my recent 6 years of career and have the ability to learn things quickly.

Core Skills

- Knowledge of PHP, MySQL, MariaDB, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Yii, JQuery, Bootstrap and UiKit
- Knowledge in MVC Software Design Pattern and Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Knowledge of Search Engine Optimization (SEO), Webmaster Tools and Google Analytics
- I can change any concept or ideas into a web application or website from scratch
- Knowledge in Social Media marketing and Google Adsense
- I'm having the ability to convert any mock-ups or prototype into web layouts and functional websites
- I'm comfortable with using Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator and therefore I craft design from the mock-ups to implementation
- Having good knowledge in Microsoft Office package

Employment History

Web Developer at Katara Cultural Village Foundation (Collaborator Staff), Doha – Qatar. (May 2016 – Present)

I have worked on the Katara projects such as Katara Novels, Katara Poet, Katara Quran, Aldadd, Katara Kahraman and S'hail. Providing IT support for the team who work on these projects.

Web Developer at Vision Web Solutions & ITQAN Technologies, Doha – Qatar. (January 2014 – April 2016)

Developed many websites and web applications from scratch as per the company requirements and I have gained good knowledge and experienced in Arabic content, RTL layouts, managing servers independently, social networks and APIs.

Web Developer at Dar Al Sharq (The Peninsula), Doha – Qatar. (October 2013 – January 2014)

I worked on the project named "Arab Cartoon Award" as a volunteer web developer. I made a complete functional website using WordPress for the project and it was my first experience on Arabic website.

Web Developer & Designer at IncitoMedia, Sri Lanka.

(*January 2011 – February 2013*)

I have gained experience and building up valuable skills with the IncitoMedia company by working in a variety of projects for the company from scratch and supervising the web development team.

Duties and Responsibilities

- Developing web applications from scratch using frameworks
- Developing websites from scratch using WordPress
- Managing and maintaining hosting servers and security independently
- Working under pressure and sometimes managing several projects at once
- Improving Search Engine Optimization of the websites using Google tools such as Webmaster Tools, Analytics etc.
- Working with Social Networks and API
- Identified problems or bugs and fixing them even from other developers' code
- Implement front-end technologies such as HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Education

EcozLabs 2012

Certified Web Designer and Developer

Veta Centre 2010

Foundation in English

Gateway Centre 2009-2010

ICDL - International Computer Driving Licence

Quantity Surveying (BTEC HND) 2007-2009

British College of Applied Studies

Personal Details

Civil Status: Married
Gender: Male
Nationality: Sri Lankan

Date of Birth: 27th of October 1988

Passport Number: N2470014

Permanent Address: No: 36, 12th Lane, 2nd Cross Street, Puttalam, Sri Lanka

References

Please do not hesitate to contact me if you require references from any of my previous employers.